

Awais Riaz

iOS Developer

- Rawalpindi, Pakistan.
- +92 310 1539343
- developer.ios.awais@gmail.com
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/awais-riaz-860b6415a/
- +923101539343
- +92 310 1539343, +971 56 245 4523

Portfolio: <a href="https://awaisriaziosdev.github.io/">https://awaisriaziosdev.github.io/</a>

# **About**

Mobile Developer with **5 years** of experience in developing, requirement gathering, designing, implementing, debugging, testing & deployment of iOS applications. During this span I have developed and maintained more than 30 iOS Apps which include Food Delivery, Fitness App, Weather forecast, Financial, Social and e- commerce Applications.

Now I'm seeking a new opportunity that will allow me to boost my skills and make myself more efficient in this rapidly changing industry.

# **Education**

Degree:- Year:-

Bachelor in Information Technology 02/2014 - 02/2018

Institute:- CGPA

PMAS Arid Agriculture University Rawalpindi, Pakistan. 3.48/4.0

# Languages and Tools

#### LANGUAGES:-

Swift, SwiftUI (Basic)

Other Language:-

C#, Flutter

Main Tool:-

Xcode

Other Tools:-

Figma, Adobe XD, Android studio, VSCode.

### Skills

CoreML, Restful API, Soap API, Versioning tools (Git), MVVM,MVC, Firebase, MapKit, Google maps, CoreData, CoreAnimation, Agile development, Push Notifications, Sqlite, Apple pay, PayPal, Stripe, Manage different environments, Third-party APIs and libraries, Handle complex JSON,

# **Experience**

# BitFalcon(Hybrid) - iOS Developer

Bahrain

June, 2022 - Present.

#### Task and Responsibilities:-

- Design, build and maintain iPhone applications.
- Integrating new features, making improvements and bug fixing in existing applications.
- Manage App Store.

### Ooober - iOS Developer

FSTP, I-9/3, Islamabad, Pakistan

Jan, 2021 - Jun, 2022

#### Task and Responsibilities:-

- Design, build Application from Scratch using MVVM or MVC in swift programming Language.
- Integrating new features, making improvements and bug fixing in existing applications.
- Manage App Store.
- Improved product quality through code review and collaboration with QA team on implementation of automation testing.
- Writing high quality code with proper OOP concepts.
- Managed tasks with Agile framework, cleared sprinted tasks

### **HQSoft** - iOS Developer

G-11 Markaz, Islamabad, Pakistan

Apr, 2020 - Jan, 2021

### Task and Responsibilities:-

- Design, build Application from Scratch using MVC in swift programming Language.
- Integrating new features, making improvements and bug fixing in existing applications.
- Work with other developers, designers, and project/business managers to develop new features consistent with the project roadmap.
- Wrote self-documenting code, easy to read and adapt for other developers.

# Appic Solutions - iOS Developer

G-11 Markaz, Islamabad, Pakistan

Nov, 2017 - Apr, 2020

### Task and Responsibilities:-

- Work with senior developers and maintain ongoing projects.
- Understand the client requirements, design and implement accordingly.
- Integrating new features, making improvements and bug fixing in applications.

# **Professional Achievements**

Project: Kharcha-Book-Expense-Manager

Appstore Link: <a href="https://apps.apple.com/pk/app/kharcha-book-expense-manager/id1608360032">https://apps.apple.com/pk/app/kharcha-book-expense-manager/id1608360032</a>

**Descriptions:** 

This budget planner App will help you save money, manage your finances, keep track of your income and expenses & plan your future in one place..

**Project: EVNGO** 

Appstore Link: <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/evngo/id1482743283">https://apps.apple.com/us/app/evngo/id1482743283</a>

**Descriptions:** 

Evngo is basically an Event based social media in its nature. The purpose of the app is to provide a platform to celebrities for creating and managing their events, where people will view and rate their events.

**Project: Walkie - Walk with Friends** 

Appstore Link: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/ walkie-walk-with-friends/id1583748274

**Descriptions:** 

Walk, Talk and Track Steps with your Friends. After walking with friends in different cities on the phone, We thought it would be great to have an app to track our progress, set goals and keep each other motivated.

Project: Couch To 5K - Run, Jog, Walk

Appstore Link: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/couch-to-5k-run-jog-walk/id419623299

**Descriptions:** 

Couch to 5K guides you with audio trainer so you know when to walk and when to run, without having to keep track of time and intervals. At the same time, you can listen to your own music. The app keeps track of your progress, starting you off on the next day's plan each time you reopen the app after completing a workout. Start session with a five-minute warmup walk or jog

Project: Mausam - Pakistan Weather App

Appstore Link: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/mausam-weather-forecast/id1600694729

**Descriptions:** 

Check your local weather forecast and stay updated in your city and favorite places around the world.

And many more..

Languages

Urdu Native

**English** Professional Working Proficiency